



## **OBJECTIVE**

Hello I am Ilias Papastratis, an AI researcher with focus on deep learning and computer vision. I have a MEng in Electrical Engineering and a MSc in Artificial Intelligence. I have worked for 4 years on research projects with challenging object, video classification and recognition tasks. What do I do in my free time? Probably, you will find me in the gym, hanging out with friends traveling or snowboarding in the winter.



### **EXPERIENCE**

## IT Coordinator | Research and Informatics Corps/ C Army Corps 03/2022 - 03/2023

Thessaloniki, Greece

- Maintenance and administration of local network with Windows Server 2016 and about 200 Windows 7/10 clients.
- Management of Domain server, File server and Active Directory
- Installation and configuration active equipment (switches, routers, computers)

## Machine Learning Researcher | Centre for Research and Technology Hellas - CERTH

10/2018 - 02/2022

Thessaloniki, Greece

Deep learning applications with video and image recognition using Python frameworks (Tensorflow, PyTorch, OpencCV, Docker and Flask)

#### Projects

- Epikoinono Android Application development for the conversion of Greek sign language into written and spoken language using deep neural networks
- QCONPASS Dynamic Quality CONtrol on Production lines using Intelligent AutonomouS vehicleS with object recognition system

Involved Technologies: Python, PyTorch, Tensorflow, OpenCV, Docker, Java, Linux

## Research Associate | Aalto University

02/2018 - 08/2018

Helsinki, Finland

GPA: 7,21/10

Co-design of control and communication protocols in Wireless Networked Control Systems Control and navigation of quadrotor aerial vehicle using Ultra Wide Band positioning system

Involved Technologies: C++, Python, ROS, Matlab



### **EDUCATION**

## MSc on Digital Media and Computational Intelligence | School of Informatics, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

10/2020 - 02/2022 GPA: 8,82/10

Main courses: Signal processing, computational vision, computational intelligence, graphics, bioinformatics

Thesis: Intrinsically disordered protein prediction for genomes and metagenomes. The main goal of the thesis was to predict intrinsic disorder using machine and deep learning networks and employ prediction methods on metagenomic data.

## MEng in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science | University of Patras 10/2012 - 07/2018

Thesis: Navigation of autonomous four-wheeled robot using Computer Vision techniques

### **Projects**

- Computational Geometry: Skeleton extraction of 3D object by Mesh Contraction, 1D Skeleton Extraction
- Design and Simulation of 4 DOF Robotic arm manipulator: Forward and Inverse Kinematics,

Dynamics, Control and Path Planning using Matlab and Robotics Toolbox

• Differential wheeled robot car programming using Accelerometer, Gyroscope and Ultrasonic



# **SKILLS**

- Python
- C++
- PyTorch
- Tensorflow
- Linux
- OpenCV

- Docker
- Matlab
- Java
- ROS
- SQL



# **LANGUAGES**

- Greek (Native)
- English (Proficient)